In this video I am going to show you how to create CUDA stream and how to perform asynchronous operations in a CUDA streams.
在这段视频中，我将向您展示如何创建CUDA流以及如何在CUDA流中执行异步操作。
Let me first introduce you to a tool called nvvp or
首先让我向您介绍一个名为nvvp的工具
NVIDIA Visual Profiler, which we are going to use to visualize our CUDA program execution.
即NVIDIA视觉分析器，我们将用它来可视化我们的CUDA程序执行情况。
Here we have a program which performs simple calculations on input data and stores the results in the device.
这里我们有一个程序，它对输入数据进行简单计算并将结果存储在设备中。
Here we have our kernel. It performs simple arithmetic operations on the input data.
这里是我们的核函数。它对输入数据执行简单的算术操作。
Since we are going to visualize the execution of this program with NVIDIA Visual Profiler, to have a clear output
因为我们将用NVIDIA视觉分析器来可视化这个程序的执行，为了得到清晰的输出
I have introduced a few iterations in the kernel as well.
我在核函数中引入了一些迭代。
The sole purpose of this for loop is to increase the execution time so we can clearly observe
这个for循环的唯一目的是增加执行时间，这样我们可以清楚地观察到
the execution in nvvp or NVIDIA Visual Profiler. That's all. And in the main file, I have performed the usual stuff.
在nvvp或NVIDIA视觉分析器中的执行情况。就这样。在主文件中，我执行了常规操作。
you've seen so far. I have initialized the input host array and transferred that data to the device and then launched the kernel
您到目前为止已经看到了。我已经初始化了输入主机数组，并将数据传输到设备上，然后启动了核函数
and wait for results to return and copy the results back to the host again. All these CUDA operations
并等待结果返回并将结果再次复制回主机。所有这些CUDA操作
are happening via the default or null stream.
都通过默认或空流进行。
Now let's look at how this program execution looks like in nvvp.
现在让我们看看这个程序在nvvp中的执行情况。
We can use nvvp to profile our kernels and have a visual output on how our kernels are going to execute
我们可以使用nvvp来分析我们的核函数，并对我们的核函数执行情况有一个视觉输出
in a particular device.
在特定设备中。
We will learn more about the nvvp tool in the upcoming CUDA tool section,
我们将在即将到来的CUDA工具部分中了解更多关于nvvp工具的信息，
but here, we are going to just use this tool to visualize CUDA program execution. So compile this program
但在这里，我们将只使用这个工具来可视化CUDA程序执行。所以编译这个程序
and then type nvvp command and executable file name. Then our program will open up in nvvp.
然后输入nvvp命令和可执行文件名。然后我们的程序将在nvvp中打开。
Initially you will be greeted with a window like this.
最初你会看到一个像这样的窗口。
Just click next and finish.
只需点击下一步并完成。
In this timeline, you can see when each CUDA operation happens.
在这个时间轴上，你可以看到每个CUDA操作的发生时间。
Now, depending on the time consumed by your kernel and data transfers, you might not see the kernel
现在，根据你的核函数和数据传输消耗的时间，你可能看不到核函数
execution properly. In such cases,
执行情况。在这种情况下，
you can expand the timeline until you can see the results clearly by holding the control key and using the mouse scroll.
你可以通过按住控制键并使用鼠标滚轮来扩展时间轴，直到你能清楚地看到结果。
Here you can see the order of your program. We perform host to device memory transfer first, then we have our kernel
在这里你可以看到你的程序的顺序。我们首先进行主机到设备的内存传输，然后是我们的核函数
execution,
执行，
and finally, we transfer the results of kernel execution back to the host.
最后，我们将核函数执行的结果传回主机。
Notice in this window, to the left, you can see a tree hierarchy which specifies the memory copies, kernel executions
注意在这个窗口的左侧，你可以看到一个树形层次结构，指定了内存复制、核函数执行
and which stream particular operations perform using these subtrees. Here all the operations we perform
以及使用这些子树执行特定操作的流。在这里，我们执行的所有操作
here happen in the default stream or null stream and it can be noticed in this subtree as well.
都发生在默认流或空流中，这也可以在这个子树中看到。
Ok,
好的，
Now you know how our usual program looks like in an nvvp timeline.
现在你知道我们的常规程序在nvvp时间轴中的样子了。
Here's what I'm going to do next.
这是我接下来要做的。
Our ultimate goal is to overlap kernel execution with memory transferring to reduce overall kernel execution time.
我们的最终目标是将核函数执行与内存传输重叠，以减少整体核函数执行时间。
For that we need two things. We should be able to launch multiple kernels and we should be able to transfer
为此我们需要两件事。我们应该能够启动多个核函数，并且能够在主机和设备之间进行传输
memory between host and device asynchronously.
异步传输内存。
So let's first look at how to perform multiple kernel launches.
那么让我们首先看看如何执行多个核函数启动。
As you may already be aware, you can simply launch multiple kernels by having that statement in the
正如你可能已经知道的那样，你可以简单地通过在主机代码中有该语句来启动多个核函数。
host code.
主机代码中。
But, by default, all these operations happen sequentially via default stream.
但是，默认情况下，所有这些操作通过默认流顺序发生。
We can overcome this limitation by creating CUDA streams.
我们可以通过创建CUDA流来克服这一限制。
CUDA streams provide a mechanism for performing operations asynchronously.
CUDA流提供了一种异步执行操作的机制。
This means that your host code does not have to wait for the CUDA kernel to finish execution before moving on to
这意味着你的主机代码不必等待CUDA核函数完成执行才能继续执行
the next statement. This allows overlapping of data transfer and kernel execution.
下一条语句。这允许数据传输和核函数执行的重叠。
So the first step in performing asynchronous operations in CUDA streams is to create the CUDA stream.
因此，在CUDA流中执行异步操作的第一步是创建CUDA流。
This can be done by declaring a stream object and calling the cudaStreamCreate function.
这可以通过声明一个流对象并调用cudaStreamCreate函数来完成。
Once the stream is created, we can pass it as an argument to our kernel launches.
一旦流创建完成，我们可以将其作为参数传递给我们的核函数启动。
The kernel launches will then be assigned to this stream and can be executed asynchronously.
核函数启动将分配到这个流中，并可以异步执行。
Additionally, we can use the cudaMemcpyAsync function to perform asynchronous memory transfers.
此外，我们可以使用cudaMemcpyAsync函数来执行异步内存传输。
Here's a quick example to demonstrate how to create and use CUDA streams.
这里有一个快速示例，展示如何创建和使用CUDA流。
First, we declare a cudaStream_t object. Then we create the stream using cudaStreamCreate.
首先，我们声明一个cudaStream_t对象。然后我们使用cudaStreamCreate创建流。
Next, we modify our kernel launch to accept the stream as an argument and pass our stream object to it.
接下来，我们修改我们的核函数启动以接受流作为参数，并将我们的流对象传递给它。
Finally, we use cudaMemcpyAsync instead of cudaMemcpy for asynchronous memory transfers.
最后，我们使用cudaMemcpyAsync而不是cudaMemcpy进行异步内存传输。
This will allow our data transfers to overlap with kernel execution, reducing overall execution time.
这将允许我们的数据传输与核函数执行重叠，从而减少整体执行时间。
That's it! You now know how to create CUDA streams and perform asynchronous operations.
就是这样！你现在知道如何创建CUDA流并执行异步操作了。